（サクラ）サスケ君！　なんで？
Sasuke!
Why?!
グルル…。
（サスケ）相変わらず
やかましいやつらだ。
You're all still as noisy as ever!
ワン！　ワン！
（キバ）てめえ！　何しに来やがった！
Why the hell
are you here, bastard?!
なんで　サスケ君が　ここに。
Why are you here, Sasuke?
いろいろあったが　俺は
木ノ葉の里を守ることに決めた。
A lot of things have happened.
I've decided to protect
the Leaf Village.
そして　俺が。
And then, I'll...
火影になる。
become Hokage.
え～！？
What?!
（ナルト）フッ　よっしゃ！
Okay then!
第七班　ここに復活だってばよ！
Team 7 is...
finally back!
行くぜ　サクラちゃん　サスケ！
Let's go, Sakura! Sasuke!
akari ga oreba kage ga dekiru to itta
You said if there's light, there are shadow
ano hi no kimi no koe ga wasure rarezu ni
I can't forget the words you said that day
tsuyoku aritai to negai
I wish to be strong
rousoku wo keshita yubi
I put out the candle with my finger
hi no watsusa ni inochi wo oboete
The heat of the flames reminded me of life
boku no koa ga hajikeru
The core of my being bursts open
guren no ai ga kokoro wo yaite
This red-hot love burns my heart
kaze ni mayoe ba namida ga ochiru
While wandering in the wind, tears start to fall
kizutsuki nagara mirai shinjite
Though I'm hurt, I believe in the future
mata saki e sono saki e
Let's go further and further ahead
gareki no sora wa bokura no kizuna
The rubble in the sky is our bond
osou mayakashi kechirashite yaru
I'll cut through the attempts to deceive me
tatakai no hate ni nani mo nakutemo
Even if there's nothing at the end of the battle
mata saki e sono saki e Ikou
Let's go further and further ahead
Team 7, Assemble!
（いの）なんか
懐かしい画じゃない？　シカマル。
That sight sure brings back memories,
doesn't it, Shikamaru?
（シカマル）どうあれ　目の前の敵を
倒すのに　協力するってんなら→
Well, if he's willing to help us
defeat the enemy,
今はしかたねえ
認めたくはねえが。
I won't turn him away.
Even though I don't want to accept him...
（チョウジ）同期が全員　揃うのって
久しぶりだよね。
It's been a long time since
our class has been back together.
この感じも　中忍試験　以来だし。
I haven't felt like this
since the Chunin Exam.
火影になんのは　俺だ！
ちょっ　お前ら　聞いてんのか！
I'm going to become Hokage!
Hey, are you guys even listening?!
（シノ）キバ　今は誰も聞いていない
惨めに見える　よせ。
Kiba, no one's paying attention
right now and it's pitiful.
Stop it.
なぜなら　いきなり出てきて
「火影になる」とのたまった→
It's because the impact of
Sasuke's sudden appearance
and his declaration to become
Hokage are much too great.
サスケのインパクトのほうが
強すぎるからだ。
（ヒナタ）キ　キバ君
私は　ちゃんと聞いてるよ。
Kiba, I heard you!
火影は
みんなが目指すものだもんね。
We should all aspire
to become Hokage!
ワン！
俺らの力　見せてやるってばよ！
Let's show them
what we're made of, ya know!
《重吾：サスケ　今　お前は何を思う》
Sasuke... What are you thinking
right now?
よ～し！
（柱間）ちょい待ち。
Okay then!
Wait a minute!
どあっ！
Huh?!
また　あれだ！
It's that thing again!
（ミナト）結界を破る気だ！
It wants to break the barrier!
Fellow previous Hokage!
先代の皆さん　気合いを
入れ直して　備えてください！
Please re-focus and
prepare yourselves!
わかっておる！
We know that!
（扉間）さ～て。
Now then...
持ちこたえた！
It held up!
なんて結界だ
あれを通さないなんて。
What an amazing barrier...
To be able to keep that thing out...
十尾は！？
Where's the Ten Tails?!
（ミフネ）フッ　十尾め
己で食らっておるわ。
That Ten Tails, he hit himself!
簡単な結界ではないぞ。
It's not some simple barrier!
すっげえ！
Wow...
（サクラ）初代様たちって
本当にすごい人たちだったのね。
The previous Hokage were
truly amazing people!
口だけではないようだな。
Looks like they weren't just all talk.
木遁　木分身の術。
Wood Style: Wood Clone Jutsu!
俺が。
結界の４面に。
I'll make entry points
on all four sides of the barrier,
忍たちの出入り口を。
作る！
so shinobi can go in and out!
俺に続け！
よし　いけぇい！
Follow me!
All right! Go!
オッス！
Right!
まだまだ！　仙法明神門。
It's not over yet!
Sage Arts: Gracious Deity Gates!
（柱間）封頭！
Head Seal!
（みんな）うお～！
さて　相手をしよう。
Now then,
time to deal with you.
（柱間）マダラ　待たせたな。
Sorry to keep you waiting, Madara...
（マダラ）いや。
No...
分身ではつまらぬ
本体が出ばるまで待つ。
A clone is no fun.
I'll wait for the real one
to show up.
今ぞ！
Now!
（みんな）うお～！
とぉ～！
分裂体か。
本体に近づけさせないつもりだな。
Fission Beings?
It's trying to keep us away
from its real body!
ひるむな！
Don't waver!
（みんな）うお～！
《サクラ：そう　私は　私は…》
Yes... I...
I...
((サスケ！
Sasuke!
風魔手裏剣　影風車！
Demon Wind Shuriken,
Windmill of Shadows!
うぉ～！
ここだ！
Over here!
ふざけんな！
Quit joking around!
口寄せの術。
Summoning Jutsu!
うっ！
フフッ　とりあえず
食らっときなさい。
Take that for now.
クソくらえ～！
Then eat this!
このガキ　まさか…。
This kid... impossible!
うわっ！
火遁　龍火の術！
Fire Style: Dragon Flame Jutsu!
(ハァ　ハァ…))
《サクラ：そう　下忍の頃から　私は→
That's right...
Ever since I was a genin,
I thought I was
a full-fledged kunoichi.
一人前のくノ一のつもりで
いたくせに→
サスケ君とナルトの後ろばかり
隠れて歩いてて。
But I ended up hiding
behind Sasuke and Naruto.
そんな私を　２人はいつも
かばって戦ってくれた。
The two of them risked everything
to protect me.
そんな自分が嫌になって→
I hated the way I was.
今度は　私の後ろ姿を見せるって
自分で…》
I swore then, that next time,
I would make them
stare at my back!
((私だって　私だって！
Even I... Even I can...
キャッ！
(今度は私の後ろ姿を
しっかり見ててください))
Now it's your turn
to gaze at my back!
《サクラ：あのとき誓ったはずなのに。
That's what I vowed back then...
サスケ君もナルトも　いつも私の前にいて
どんどん突き進んでいくから→
But Naruto and Sasuke kept
progressing faster and faster...
私　やっぱり追いつけないやって→
So I gave up...
Thinking it was useless
because they were just too strong!
２人とも強すぎるから
しかたないやって諦めて　でも…》
I thought I'd never be able
to catch up to them.
But...
((ナルト！
サスケ！
Naruto!
Sasuke!
やめて！
Stop!
(２人ともやめて！))
Both of you, stop!
《サクラ：何も考えず　ただナルトに
重荷を背負わせてしまった》
I didn't think about it...
and I put the entire burden
on Naruto.
《サクラ：私は泣きついただけ。
I went crying to you.
あなたに頼って
すがりついただけ》
I held onto you, expecting you
to make it all better.
《サクラ：自分じゃ何も…》
While I did nothing.
I'm sorry, Naruto.
((ごめん　ナルト。　少し
待たせることになっちゃうけど→
You may have to wait
for me a little bit.
今度は私も一緒に。
Next time I'm coming with you!
私を弟子にしてください。
（綱手）フフッ。
Please take me on as your apprentice!
しゃんなろ～！
Shannaro!
だいぶ動きがよくなったな。
Your movements are getting better!
ところで　最初に教えたことを
覚えているか？
By the way, do you remember
the first thing I taught you?
もちろんです。
医療忍者は決して死なぬこと。
Of course.
Medic Ninja must never
get themselves killed.
だから前にでしゃばるような
ことを決してしては…。
Thus they must never force
their way forward.
もちろんそうだ。　だがそれは→
That is true...
However, that does not mean that
前で戦うための術を覚えない
という理由にはならない。
you don't have to learn jutsu
necessary to fight on the frontline.
なにより　あなたは私の弟子。
First and foremost,
you are my disciple.
三忍の力を受け継ぐ　くノ一。
A kunoichi who will inherit
the power of the Legendary Sannin.
And... Sakura Haruno...
そして　春野サクラ　あなたは→
You are also the disciple
of the Fifth Hokage!
(五代目火影の
弟子でもあるのだから))
And...
今　たまりきった。
やっと開放できる。
I just now reached full capacity.
And I can finally unleash it!
ギ～ッ！
しゃんなろ～！
Shannaro!
《二度と　もう二度と…。
I am never, ever talking back
to Sakura ever again.
二度とサクラちゃんに
歯向かうのはよそう。
She'll destroy me.
塵にされる》
なんという怪力。
あれは綱以上かもしれんな。
What monster strength!
It might just be greater than Tsuna's!
《３年間　チャクラを
一定にため続ける。
Amassing chakra at a continuous rate
over three years...
至極緻密なチャクラコントロール。
requiring extremely
delicate chakra control.
私でもできなかった百豪の印》
The 100 Healings Mark
that I couldn't even achieve.
私は若づくりする必要がない分ね。
And I have no need to keep up
a youthful appearance!
風遁！
炎遁！
Wind Style...
Inferno Style...
螺旋手裏剣！
加具土命！
- Rasen Shuriken!
- Flame Control!
サスケ君！
Sasuke!
って　あの…
俺もいんだけど？　サクラちゃん。
Um...
I'm here too... Sakura!
足を引っ張るなよ　ナルト。
Don't drag us down, Naruto.
そうよ　細かいこと言ってると
私が火影の座　ぶんどるわよ。
He's right! Keep complaining and
I'll just grab the title
of Hokage away from you!
って　え！？
サクラちゃんまでその気？
Huh?
Not you too, Sakura?!
今度は背中合わせでいくわよ。
This time, we fight with
our backs to each other!
《綱手様　私→
Lady Tsunade...
I've finally caught up
with these two.
やっと２人に
追いつけたみたいです》
《これが九尾のチャクラを
コントロールした状態か》
So this is how Nine Tails
Chakra looks under control...
《新しい写輪眼。　黒い炎》
A new Sharingan...
with black flames...
《ナルトのやつ　螺旋丸の
性質変化までちゃんと…》
That Naruto...
He's even mastered changing
the Rasengan's nature...
フフフッ。
Sakura's holding her own!
やるじゃない　サクラも。
クーッ！　おい　第八班もいくぞ　コラ！
Hey, Team 8! Let's go too!
We can't let Team 7 show us up!
七班なんかに負けねえ！
うん。
Right!
俺だって新術開発してたんだ
っつうの　ナルト。
I've worked out
a new jutsu too, Naruto!
これがてめえだけの術だと
思うなよ。
Don't think you're the only one
with this jutsu!
《影分身の術！》
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
影分身だあ？　たった１人
増えただけじゃねえか。
Did you just say Shadow Clone Jutsu?
All you did was make one clone!
Back in the day,
I could make a lot more...
昔の俺のほうが　まだ…。
いいから見てろ！
Just watch!
There may be just one,
but he's three times stronger!
頭１つ増えただけで
ふだんの３倍の力だってんだ。
来い　赤丸！
Come on, Akamaru!
ワン！
We're gonna attack the enemy!
敵の中に突っ込むぞ。
《犬塚流　人獣混合変化》
Inuzuka Style!
Man-Beast Team
Transformation Combo!
（キバ）参頭狼！
Three-Headed Wolf!
（キバ）ケッ　サスケのギャグは胸クソわりいが→
Sasuke's joke was disgusting.
But it's revving me up!
不思議とテンション上がっちまうぜ。
Tail Chasing...
（キバ）尾追い　牙牙転牙！
Rotating Fang!
Parasitic Gigantic Beetle...
（シノ）寄大蟲。
虫食い。
Infestation!
Gross! What are those?!
キモ！　何なのよ　これ。
寄大蟲…　体内で与える
チャクラの量を間違えると→
Parasitic Gigantic Beetles...
If you mistake the amount
of chakra to give them,
they'll devour your flesh
and undergo rapid growth.
肉をむさぼり　急成長する。
寄生させておくのが難しい蟲だ。
They are beetles
that are difficult to nurture.
Two Palms! Four Palms! Eight Palms!
（ヒナタ）二掌　四掌
八掌　十六掌→
Sixteen Palms!
Thirty-Two Palms!
三十二掌！
《クッ…　やっぱり
ここまでが私の…》
I guess this is still my limit...
No such thing.
((ネジ：そんなことはありません。
（ヒナタ）でも私
ネジ兄さんのようにはとても…。
But I'm not like you, Neji...
If you set limits on yourself,
（ネジ）限界を決めてしまっては
あいつに追いつけませんよ。
you'll never be able
to catch up to him...
己の限界を乗り越え
そこから恐れず→
Overcome your limits,
fearlessly take a giant leap forward.
(大きく踏み出すんです。
それが…))
That's the...
Sixty-Four Palms!
六十四掌。
((ネジ：六十四掌へつなげるコツです))
... trick to achieve the Sixty-Four Palms.
Naruto is always striving
to get ahead.
《ヒナタ：ナルト君は　いつも→
前へ進もうと頑張って　私は…》
And I...
... want to keep standing
by Naruto forever!
《ナルト君の横に
ずっといたいんだもの》
今度は　これのまま
八卦六十四掌までいきます。
This time, I'll proceed to
Eight Trigrams
Sixty-Four Palms like this!
《だから　いつだって
一歩でも前へ》
So I'll continuously
move forward as well!
私たち第十班は
猪鹿蝶のコンビネーションでいくよ。
Come on, Team 10!
Let's attack with
the Ino-Shika-Cho Combination!
フォーメーションＥだ。
Formation E!
This isn't the Chunin Exam.
はあ　中忍試験じゃあるまいし→
We're not competing against
the other teams.
班で張り合うことはねえだろうが。
今は　戦争中だぞ。
This is war...
But we want to show them
what we're made of, right?
でも　見せ場は欲しいよね。
《倍化の術》
Expansion Jutsu!
ったく…。
Shadow Grasping Jutsu!
《影掴みの術》
Twenty-five enemy signatures
picked up and locked on!
《敵　２５体　感知オーケー　ロックオン》
感知伝々。
Sensory Relay!
Human Boulder Yo-Yo!
（チョウジ）肉弾用々。
更に倍化するよ。
I'm going to expand even more.
Can you handle more weight?
重くなるけど　いける？
Yeah... You're still light.
ああ　まだ軽いほうだし。
それに　これじゃ
見せ場にちょいと足りてねえしな。
And besides, this isn't quite flashy
enough to impress.
What? Who's being
super competitive now?
何よ　張り合う気　満々じゃない。
（サイ）僕も一応
第七班なんですけどね。
Actually, I'm technically on
Team 7 too, you know...
《サイ：僕は　一気に
空から本体を攻める》
I'll quickly attack
the main body from the air!
サイ。
Sai!
うっ…。
サイ。
Sai!
Are you all right?!
大丈夫か？
ああ。
Yes...
うわっ。
ダメだ。
It's no good!
The enemy keeps
increasing in numbers.
どんどん敵の数が増えてくる。
そのうえ　でかいのまで。
Not only that...
Some are huge!
このサイズは　さすがに重いな。
These big ones... sure are heavy!
ナルト　また　みんなに
チャクラを渡せないのかい？
Naruto...
Can you share your chakra
with everyone again?
今は無理だ。
I can't right now!
Kurama hasn't finished
amassing chakra yet!
九喇嘛のチャクラが
まだ　たまりきってねえ。
本体を倒すには
あのデカブツをなぎ払いつつ→
In order to take down
the main body,
we need to mow down
the big ones and slip past them.
間をすり抜けていくしか方法が…。
The distance is too great to
make a single leap for it.
一気にジャンプして
近づける距離でもない。
敵の攻撃を弾き
印を結ぶ時間もいる。
We also need time to weave signs
and repel the enemy's attacks.
ナルトのチャクラがない以上
深手を負う可能性が高いのに→
Without your chakra, Naruto,
it's very likely
we'll suffer heavy casualties.
And the Medical Corps
can't come up to the front.
医療班は　前に出られない。
Mow down and slip past?
なぎ払い　すり抜ける
何の造作もない。
Easy.
一気にジャンプして近づけるうえに→
This guy has the power to
clear the distance in a single leap
and repel enemy attacks.
攻撃も弾く力もあんぜ　こいつは。
みんなが深手を負っても→
I can now stay nearby and
常にそばにいて
回復してあげられる　今の私なら。
heal anyone who suffers
serious injuries at all times.
（３人）口寄せの術。
- Summoning Jutsu!
koushite ima mo kawarazu
Even now, I haven't changed
donna tsuyoi nami ni mo sakarau
I'll fight any wave, no matter how strong it is
soko ni wa nakama, haruka kanata
My friends are far away
deatta subete ga ore no takara
Everyone I meet is my treasure
kono sora e habataiteku
I'll fly through this sky
ore kara shinjiru anata ni eeru
I believe in you and I'll yell out to you
toki ni wa warai naite
Sometimes I laugh or cry
donna ni fumareyouto hana wa saiteru
The flowers still bloom,
no matter how many times they've been trampled on
datte kimetakara
It's because I've made up my mind
donna ni fumarete mo saiteta hana
I'll rise up like a blooming flower
no you ni motto takaku
No matter how many times it gets trampled
sore ga naniyori mo chikara hanatsu
It unleashes more power than anything
aitsu no bun made tsuyoku ikite
I want to live resiliently for their sake too
dare ni mo makenai tsuyoi ishide
With a powerful will, I won't give in to anyone
susume kitto susumeru
Move ahead, I'm sure I'll move ahead
dare mo mitakotonai sekai wo tsukureru
I can create a world that no one has seen before
kowakunai soba ni iru kagiri
I'm not afraid, as long as you're by my side
mawari ni wa nakama ya famirii
Surrounded by friends and family
sono chikara ga michishirube ni naru
Their power shows me the way
minna kara moratta kono te ni love
In my hand, I hold what everyone has given me Love
kono machi ni fuku kaze ni noru
I'll ride the wind that blows through this city
gooru wa mada hodo tooku
I'm still a long way from my goal
demo shitteru mada yare n datte
But I know that I can still go on
dakara sakebu kono koe kareru made
So I'll cry out until I lose my voice
kono sekai wa mienu mono bakari de
This world is full of things I can't see
kowai kara jibunjishin wo kizutsuketa
I hurt myself because I was afraid of them
kirisaita yami no saki ni mieta mono
When I cut through the darkness, I saw something
massugu ni misueta mama de
I continue to gaze straight ahead
hanasanai
And never let go
See the gigantic guy
way in the back?
Could you get me closer
to it with a big leap?
I need you to just
keep advancing forward.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
I'll get the real body in the back.
美空ひばりです。
Lady Katsuyu,
please divide and
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
attend to each person
in the Allied Shinobi Forces.
Our role will be to heal everyone.
お楽しみください。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The New Three-Way Deadlock."
『木曜８時のコンサート　名曲！
にっぽんの歌』　２時間スペシャル。
It is a new era!
今回は　スペシャルならではの→